visualrecipes.com 2017-02-22

# Privacy Policy | Visual Recipes

Home > Privacy Policy

Effective Date: January 15, 2009

Pixel Owl, LLC (hereinafter “Visual”) adopts this Privacy Policy to provide you with information on how Visual collects and treats your personal or personally identifiable information, including but not limited to your email address, IP address, usage statistics, name, photographs, logos, avatars, location information, and any other information you voluntarily provide (hereinafter “Personal Information”) when you visit or use the Website. This Privacy Policy does not apply to individuals or entities that are not under the actual control of Visual.

**1\. Collection and Use of Personal Information.** Visual may collect Personal Information when you use the Website. Visual uses your Personal Information to help you register a user account, to verify and activate your user account, to communicate with you, to provide you with services and support, to provide you with Visual’s newsletter or Contest information, to tailor your experience of the Website, and to update you on Visual’s services and benefits. This Personal Information may include your email address, your name, your IP address, usage statistics, your sex or gender, your physical location, and other information.

You agree that Visual is allowed to use your email address, however obtained, to communicate with you, to provide you with support, to provide you with Visual’s newsletter or Contest information, and to update you on our services. By submitting your Personal Information to Visual, you agree that Visual may contact you.

Visual may collect data about your use of the Website that is not associated with your specific personal identity. Visual may log your IP address when you use the Website or collect other information via cookies to evaluate how you use the Website in order to tailor the Website according to your preferences.

**2\. Sharing and Disclosure of Your Personal Information.** Visual will not transfer, sell, lease, or rent your Personal Information to any individual, business, or government entity, except to respond to duly authorized information requests by government authorities, comply with any law, regulation, subpoena, or court order, help prevent fraud or to enforce or protect Visual’s rights or properties, or to protect the personal safety of Visual’s employees and third parties on Visual’s property. Visual warrants that it will comply with all applicable state and federal laws concerning the transfer of personal information.

**3\. Personal Information and Opt-Out.** Visual does not use your Personal Information for advertisements by third parties; however, third party advertisers that advertise on the Website may collect information from and store information in cookies, web beacons, pixel tags, or clear GIFs located on your computer or the Website. You understand and agree that Visual is not responsible for any use of your personal information by a third-party advertiser, including a third-party advertiser’s use of cookies, web beacons, pixel tags, or clear GIFs. To learn more about this “behavioral advertising” practice or to opt-out of this use of your anonymous information, you can visit [networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/). Visual may use your Personal Information, including your email address and any communications sent from that address, consistent with the provisions outlined above.

You are permitted to opt-out of communications from Visual through your user account control panel.

**4\. Visual’s Sale or Purchase of a Business Unit or Subsidiary.** If Visual acquires or sells a business unit or subsidiary, including but not limited to the complete sale of the Website to a third party, your Personal Information may be transferred to a third party. If this occurs, your Personal Information will continue to be used consistent with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

**5\. User Accounts.** Visual may provide you with a username and password to access or use certain components of the Website or to participate in Contests. If Visual assigns you a username and password, you have the ability to edit your Personal Information at any time. You may also request, in writing, that Visual cancel your user account. Visual will not share your user account information with another individual, business, or government entity except as otherwise provided in this Agreement.

Visual, through the use of third-party application programming interfaces (APIs), may provide you with the ability to authenticate your identity through a third-party service in order to access or use certain components of the Website. These third party authentication or access control systems may provide Visual with access to content or information that you have provided to third party services. You understand and agree that Visual is not responsible for your use of third-party user authentication or access control systems and that your relationship with those systems are governed by their own terms of use agreements and privacy policies.

**6\. Protection of Your Personal Information.** All user accounts must be access with usernames and passwords. You are advised not to share any unnecessary Personal Information, including your username and password, with any other person or entity.

**7\. Integrity of Personal Information.** You are responsible for ensuring that your Personal Information is accurate, complete, current, and relevant. You have an ongoing duty to inform Visual of any changes in your Personal Information.

**8\. Changes and Amendments.** Visual reserves the right to amend or change this Privacy Policy at any time. If Visual changes or amends this Privacy Policy, the Effective Date of the Privacy Policy will change.

**9\. Contact.** You may direct all questions and concerns regarding this Privacy Policy to Visual by emailing [help@visualrecipes.com](mailto:help@visualrecipes.com) . You may also contact Visual in writing at:

Visualrecipes.com  
P.O. Box 240474  
St. Paul, MN 55124-0474
